TENGOKU-DAIMAKYO
《天国大魔境》 （推动发车）
Water--
水啊…
Oh, this place.
这个地方哦
If you go a little past that elevated track,
过了那个高架桥之后，再往前走一些
there's an underground entrance.
就会见到一个地下道入口
Water gets collected over there.
水都囤积在那里
Thanks for the help.
谢谢你的帮忙
Hey, do you need a place to sleep?
你们需要一个睡觉的地方吗？
HOTEL CLEAN FUTONS
（旅馆） （干净床垫）
I have clean rooms and aired-out futons, you know.
我已把房间打扫干净，床垫也充气好了
Sorry, but we're just passing through.
抱歉，但我们只是路过这里而已
I see.
是哦
Well,
其实
it'd be good to leave our bags while we get water.
把行李留下来再去取水也挺好的
Since the water will be heavy.
因为水很重
You did that just to give her money.
你这么做只是为了给她钱
You're too nice. What if she steals everything?
你人太好了啦 如果她偷光了我们的东西呢？
We don't have anything worth stealing.
我们又没什么值钱的东西好被偷的
She even told us to take our money and valuables with us.
她甚至还提醒我们 把钱和贵重物品带在身上
Let's trust her.
我们就相信她吧
100% SAFE WATER
《百分百安全的水》
Look.
你看
Isn't this it? The underground entrance.
地下道入口就在那里吧？
BICYCLE PARKING - OPEN 24 HOURS
（自行车停放处，24小时开放）
It's water.
有水
But isn't it just collecting here?
但这只是积水吧？
It doesn't look very clean.
看起来不太干净
SUBWAY
（地铁）
Someone's collapsed over there!
有人在那里倒下了
Maru! Don't jump recklessly into the water!
小丸，别那么莽撞地就跳进水里
That looks really bad.
看起来很糟糕
Is he still alive?
他还活着吗？
My buddy…
我的兄弟…
Help my buddy.
救救我的兄弟
It was a monster.
有一个怪物
My buddy…
我兄弟他…
Help…
救救他…
-That guy's a goner. -Sis.
-那个人没救了 -姐
Run!
快跑
It worked.
成功了
It took an extra shot, but…
多开了一枪，但是…
Look. It's out cold.
看吧，它一动也不动了
Once you know it's gonna chase you, it's easy to come up with a plan.
一旦知道了它会追上来 很容易就能想出办法
Your quick thinking is really amazing.
你敏捷的思维真是太强了
Hurry up and kill it, Maru.
小丸，快点杀了它
Oh, right.
好的
All right.
来咯
Fatal Dive!
致命深潜
Fatal Dive! Fatal Dive!
致命深潜…致命深潜
Why…
怎么会？
It's not a Hiruko! It's a wild animal!
它不是蛭子，它是野生动物
What? No way!
什么？真的假的？
Over there, Maru!
那里，小丸
Sis, wait!
姐，等等
Here. Hurry up!
这里，动作快
W-wait!
等等
Climb up!
往上爬
Good thing I managed to get up here.
好险我想办法上来了
It's a bear! A bear!
是一只熊，一只熊！
Can you imagine how that felt, Sis?
你能体会那是什么感觉吗，姐？
Just when I was thinking,
正当我在想着
"Huh? It's not going in. That's weird."
「咦？进不去，好奇怪」的时候
I met the bear's eyes from this distance!
突然就和一只熊四目相对，靠得这么近
Sorry! Sorry! Sorry!
对不起啦…真抱歉
That guy said it was a monster!
都是那个人说有一个怪物
Don't blame it on someone else!
别把错推到别人头上
That bear basically is a monster!
那只熊基本上就是一个怪物啊
But it's a good thing it's a bear. It can't climb up.
但好险是一只熊，它爬不上来
We'd be done for if it was a gorilla.
如果是大猩猩的话，我们就完蛋了
Not good.
不妙
It's getting cold.
越来越冷了
Wait. Where did the bear go?
等等，熊跑到哪里去了？
It kept walking around, but it's gone now.
它刚刚一直走来走去，但现在不见了
Let's take the chance to get away.
我们趁机逃走吧
If the fourth bullet fires, I've got one shot left.
如果开了第四枪，我就只剩最后一发了
Will it shoot?
能成功射出吗？
I'll warm up the battery.
我先预热一下电池吧
Uh-oh.
不妙
What? "Uh-oh"?
什么不妙？
Three choices.
三个选择
One. I dropped the battery.
第一，我让电池掉下去了
Two. Well--
第二，这个嘛…
That is--
就是…
What are you doing?
你在搞什么？
Geez, it really fell.
天啊，真的掉下去了
-Go get it. -Stop joking.
-去把电池捡回来 -别开玩笑了
What if the bear is still around?
如果熊还在附近呢？
Maru.
小丸
Do you see me as a woman? Or a man?
你把我看作是个女人还是个男人？
What? What's with that question?
什么？这是什么问题？
Well, you look like a woman, so--
你看起来像个女人，所以…
I guess that's probably not what you want to hear, but…
这或许不是你想听到的答案，但是…
Okay!
就这么办
I'll let you touch my boobs if you get it--
如果你把电池捡回来，我就让你摸胸
He jumped!
他跳下去了
That idiot!
那个白痴
Maru!
小丸
There it is!
熊在那里
It was hiding and waiting for us to come down.
它躲起来等我们下来
It's definitely targeting us.
它肯定是锁定我们了
We can wait it out forever up here
我们可以在这里等一辈子
or get down and shoot it when it's in range.
或者下去 等它到了射程范围之内时对它开枪
Damn it.
该死
Maru,
小丸
I managed to climb up from the adrenaline rush,
我是靠着肾上腺素爆发才爬上来的
but I can't climb down from here.
但我没办法从这里爬下去
-What? -No, see.
-什么？ -你要知道…
It's not normal to be as tough as you.
像你这么耐操的人不多见
Normal people can't handle this height!
一般人没办法在这种高度爬上爬下
So Maru,
所以，小丸
this time, go down with the Kiru-Beam and kill the bear.
这一次你带着贵留光线下去，杀了那只熊
Then I'll use the dead bear as a cushion and get down.
然后我就可以利用熊的尸体做为护垫 从这里下去
As long as it's not a Man-eater, all you need is one shot to the head.
只要它不是食人者 你只需要朝它头部开一枪即可
Let me tell you one thing, Sis.
我也告诉你一件事吧，姐
Even if you give me the gun, I can't shoot as accurately as you.
即便你把枪给我 我的枪法也没办法像你这么准
Am I that good of a shot?
我的枪法很准吗？
Yeah, you're really good.
对呀，你超强的
Normally, you can't shoot a power pole while climbing a fence
一般人没办法一边爬越围栏 一边还能射中电线杆
or aim for the enemy's arm while running.
或者在逃跑的同时还能射中敌人的手臂
Am I helpful?
我能帮上忙？
Of course you are.
当然咯
I would've died five times already without you.
如果不是你的话，我已经死了五次了
Sis?
姐？
I'm help--
我能帮上忙…
I want to be helpful to Robin.
我希望能够帮助到露敏
I'm not playing around! I told you not to come. It's dangerous!
我不是在开玩笑的 我叫你别来，很危险耶
I'll drive it away.
我会赶走它
I know I can do it.
我知道我办得到
Okay!
好吧
Let's make a new plan.
重新拟定战略
First, wait for the bear to get far away while warming up our bodies.
首先，我们一边热身，一边等待熊走远
And once it's far away?
它走远了之后呢？
Maru, you use that chance to get down.
小丸，你就趁机下去
I'll come down as soon as I hear you land.
我一听到你成功落地后，我紧接着跟上
Then you run as fast as you can after catching me.
接我落地之后，你就拼命逃跑
What about you? What if the fourth shot doesn't fire?
那你呢？如果无法成功发射第四枪呢？
If that happens…
如果发生这种事的话…
I'll hold it off until you get away.
我会力撑到你逃走为止
Why didn't you get away?
你为什么没逃走？
You actually thought I'd run away alone? That hurts.
你真的以为我会独自逃走？真令我心寒
And it was a flaw in your plan.
你的战略出现了这个漏洞
I was confident the fourth shot would fire.
我很有信心第四枪一定能发射成功
What?
什么？
The battery was charged with your horny energy!
因为电池充饱了你的好色电力
What the hell? Stop that!
搞什么啦？你住嘴啦
Hey!
喂
Iwata! Hang in there! Iwata!
岩田，撑住啊，岩田
-Boss. -Shimomoto didn't make it.
-老大 -下元没活下来
Totori.
都都里
What about the people who saved Iwata?
救了岩田的人呢？
They said their names weren't worth it and left like the wind.
他们说他们的名字不值得一提 然后像一阵风似地离开了
For real?
真的吗？
Who were they? The bear's head was completely blown away.
他们是何方神圣？熊头整个爆裂了
HOTEL
（旅馆）
-I wanted to meet them. -Yeah.
-我想要见见他们 -对呀
To think there'd be a bear around here--
没想到竟然会有熊在这里出没
It's so nice animals aren't like Hiruko.
真好，动物跟蛭子不一样
Their carcasses don't disappear and we can eat them.
它们的残骸不会消失，我们就能拿来吃
I'll tell you how we got tricked, so you can keep it in mind.
我会告诉你我们是怎么被骗的 让你记住这个教训
We got tricked?
我们被骗了？
The vigilantes in the tent city were also bandits.
帐蓬村那些自卫队队员同时也是一帮恶棍
We were completely lured into their hunting grounds.
我们毫无戒心地被诱拐到他们的狩猎场
Lured?
诱拐？
100% safe water.
百分百安全的水
I'm sure their plan was to block
我相信他们原本计划
the underground entrance once we got close.
在我们一进入地下道时就挡住入口
That map-seller must've been in on it too.
卖地图的人一定也是一伙的
Then we can't trust anything on the map.
那么我们就完全不能相信这份地图咯
It might not all be fake.
地图倒不见得都是骗人的
That's enough regretting. Let's sleep.
反省够了，该睡觉了
We're stuck here anyway.
反正我们被困在这里了
What's wrong?
怎么了吗？
She gave us two rooms, so let's sleep comfortably on our own.
她给了我们两间房 我们就各自单独好好睡一觉吧
Did you forget something?
你是不是忘了一件事？
Did you forget about your promise, Sis?
你忘了你答应过我的事吗，姐？
I risked my life, you know.
我可是冒了生命危险
Let me touch your boobs.
让我摸你的胸吧
HOTEL
（旅馆）
My sister's hair was originally black and straight.
我姐姐的头发本来是黑色的直发
It seems your hair can change
看来因为重伤动过大手术之后
after undergoing surgery for a major injury.
头发也会跟着改变
That's probably why I started growing this red, dry hair.
这可能就是我新长出的头发 为什么是红色而且很干燥的原因吧
But I think it's a curse from my sister.
但我认为这是我姐姐的诅咒
Saying "Don't mess with my body!"
像是在说：「别任意侵犯我的身体」
I see.
是哦
Now take off your jacket.
把外套脱掉吧
You sure? Touching my boobs means this, you know.
你确定？摸我的胸部也就表示…你懂吗？
If you still say it doesn't matter, then I'll keep my promise.
如果你仍然觉得这样也无所谓 我就会说到做到
Because it's a promise between men!
因为这是男人之间的约定
Wai-- Rules! Let's set some rules.
等等，规则，我们先订下一些规则
Like how many sec--
像是几秒钟…
That sounded just like a girl.
那像是女孩发出的声音
Hey, you two.
喂，你们两个
PLEASE KEEP THE ROOMS CLEAN
（请保持房间整洁）
PLEASE DON'T DIRTY THE FUTON
（请别把床垫弄脏）
This is not the place for doing that!
这个地方不是让你们用来做这种事的
-You, come this way. -Wait.
-你，跟我来 -等等
Sir,
先生
how about me?
你觉得我怎么样？
Eight hundred thousand.
80万
Or that solar-powered light!
或者是那个太阳能灯
That will be enough.
那也就够了
So you did go through our stuff.
你果然偷翻了我们的东西
I didn't take anything, so what's the problem?
我没有拿走任何东西，有什么关系吗？
So how about it?
你觉得如何？
Should I keep the bandana on?
我不该把发带解下来，对吧？
Call me Totori. I don't know my last name.
叫我都都里，我不知道我姓什么
Hey, I'm good.
不用了
Do you know what "no, thank you" means?
你知道「不用了，谢谢」是什么意思吗？
I prefer older girls--
我比较喜欢年长的女生
You--
你…
Sis! Get over here!
姐！快过来！
What're you doing?
你在做什么？
Don't move.
别动
Sis!
姐
What's wrong, Maru?
怎么了，小丸？
-I got in! -Ouch! It hurts!
-我进去了 -唉哟，很痛耶
What went in where?
什么东西进去了哪里？
What did you do?
你做了什么？
No…
不是啦
After realizing the difficulties of having to explain
在体认到在这种状况之下，要将种种误会
the various misunderstandings of this situation,
解释清楚有多困难之后
all Maru could see was the dark depths of his despair.
小丸能见到的只有那有如黑暗深渊的绝望
There are no signs of an illness.
没有生病的迹象
Really? What a relief.
真的吗？那我就放心了
You show signs of fatigue. Please take a nap here.
你有一些疲惫的现象，请在这里睡个午觉
Who's there?
谁在那里？
What?
这是？
Asura?
亚思拉？
What are you good at, Tokio?
时男，你有什么擅长的事？
What do you mean?
这是什么意思？
It disappeared.
消失了
What? My leg is--
什么？我的腿…
Doctor! Doctor!
医生，医生
A dream?
一场梦？
How are you feeling?
你觉得怎么样？
I'm fine.
我很好
DON'T COME IN
（别进来）
We are really sorry!
我们真的很抱歉
My heaven is right here.
我的天国就在这里
I will take full responsibility. Please forgive me.
我会负起全责，请原谅我
Well, I don't mind if we continue chatting like this.
我是不介意我们像这样继续聊下去啦
But you look so pitiful, so let's stop here.
但你们看起来好可怜，起来吧
You didn't do anything wrong. I was the one who came on to you.
你没做错任何事，是我主动上门的
Thank you!
谢谢
TOTORI'S HOTEL
（都都里的旅馆）
Even if you ask me what I am, I'm just your average orphan.
我的来历吗？我不过就是一个普通的孤儿
I can only remember being raised by those vigilantes.
我只记得我是那些恶棍养大的
So you were born after the Great Disaster, and raised as an orphan?
所以你是出生在大灾难之后 被当成孤儿养大的？
But your parents could be alive somewhere.
但你的父母可能还活着
It's not like I want to look for them. Or meet them.
我一点都不想寻找他们，或者跟他们相认
I've realized something.
我明白了一件事
Anything that feels good makes money.
让人觉得舒服的事就能赚钱
I'll earn money by getting more clean rooms and futons.
如果我有更多干净的房间和床垫 就能够赚更多的钱
I'll have sex with the customers I like,
遇到我喜欢的客人，我就会跟他们上床
and become the King of Hotels!
最后就会成为一名旅馆大亨
I don't get why I can enter a human.
我不明白为什么我能伸入人类的身体
But good thing I cleared up that misunderstanding.
但好险我把那个误会澄清了
I thought the only way I was gonna get you to believe me,
我还以为唯一能够让你相信我的办法
was by killing her with the Maru-Touch.
是用小丸触碰杀了她
Oh, yeah? Wasn't it the Whatchamacallit Dive?
不是应该叫什么什么深潜吗？
Forget that ever happened!
请你忘了那件事好吗？
I knew it was bad the second I said it.
我一说出口就立刻觉得烂透了
I remember now. Fatal Dive.
我想起来了，是致命深潜
I told you to forget it!
我就叫你忘了这件事
HOTEL
（旅馆）
Well, see ya.
再见咯
The futon was really comfortable.
床垫真的很舒服
What's up? You don't look too good.
怎么了？你看起来没精打采的
What happened to all that energy from last night?
你昨晚那些精力呢？
They said the Boss didn't make it.
他们说老大没能撑下来
He died early in the morning.
他今天早上过世了
Even though you saved him.
尽管你们救了他
He was so tough. I didn't think he would die.
他很强悍，我从没想过他会死
He was a good boss. So kind to us.
他是个很棒的老大，很照顾我们
Well, dying is a part of life.
也罢，死亡是人生必经的过程
Want to join us?
想跟我们一起走吗？
Okay.
好的
Then be the King of Hotels.
那就要成为旅馆大亨哦！
Even a guy like that was important to somebody.
就连他那种人，对某人来说也意义重大
If I was born and raised in this area,
如果我在这种地方出生长大
I might've been one of his guys.
我也可能会成为他手底下的人
You look better today.
你今天看起来好多了
I was worried about something, but it's all better now.
我本来有些担心，但现在没事了
That's good.
那就好
DETECTING DETAILED POINTS
（侦测细节点）
COMPARISON IN PROGRESS INSPECTION COMPLETE
（比对进行中） （验证完成）
FEATURES - 92% MATCH OBJECTS APPEAR IDENTICAL
（特征一致率：92%） （显示为相同目标物）
I found it. This is it.
我找到了，就是它
The footprint in this room is…
这个房间所出现的鞋印是…
Tokio's.
时男的
But how? Without anyone noticing?
但怎么可能没有任何人发现？
I saw Asura's ghost today.
我今天见到了亚思拉的鬼魂
Ghost?
鬼魂？
But it might have been a dream.
但也有可能是做梦啦
You liked Asura, right?
你喜欢亚思拉，对吧？
Yeah.
对
But it's different to my love for you.
但跟我对你的爱是不一样的
You know that, right?
你明白的，对吧？
Yeah.
对
Translated by Annie Chen
字幕翻译：欧德慧